# RACHEL SUTER

rachellsuter@gmail.com • rsuterdesign.com • 201-803-4881

Email & Digital Ad Design

Microsoft Office

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

**SKILLS** 

Current graphic designer at Conscious Step, a brand that connects consumers with nonprofits, and recent Computer Science graduate with a passion for using digital communication and design to educate and create positive change.

Adobe Creative Suite

SKILLS	<ul> <li>HTML/CSS</li> <li>HZ Research &amp; Web Design</li> <li>Motion Graphics</li> <li>Social Media</li> <li>Figma</li> </ul>
WORK HISTORY	
Sep 2023 - Present	<ul> <li>Graphic Designer   Conscious Step</li> <li>Email, social &amp; digital design for lifestlye brand that connects consumers with nonprofits.</li> </ul>
Nov 2022 - Present	<ul> <li>Member &amp; Voluneer Designer   Closter Environmental Commission</li> <li>Design and update <u>sustainablecloster.org</u> website.</li> <li>Create social media posts to educate community and advertise events.</li> </ul>
May 2022 - Present	<ul> <li>Print Designer, Website &amp; Blog Manager   Capitol Express Tours</li> <li>Manage WordPress website &amp; write blogs for DC national park tour business.</li> <li>Design leaflets and brochures for marketing material for print.</li> </ul>
Sep 2022 - Sep 2023	<ul> <li>Junior Graphic Designer   Elemis</li> <li>Design onsite, email, and banner display ads using Photoshop, Illustrator, &amp; After Effects.</li> <li>Create designs &amp; animations for social content, presentations, &amp; marketing campaigns.</li> </ul>
Aug 2022 - Dec 2022	<ul> <li>Social Media Graphic Designer   Nuthatch Naturals</li> <li>Create images and animations for children's skincare start-up brand social media.</li> <li>Analyze social media insights and improve engagement of customers.</li> </ul>
Oct 2021 - Jun 2022	<ul> <li>Graphic Designer &amp; Website Assistant   EnviroFest International &amp; Sustainability</li> <li>Assist non-profit &amp; sustainability focused educational organizations with WordPress.</li> <li>Design flyers &amp; banners for print to advertise panel at COP26 &amp; create newsletters.</li> </ul>
Jan 2022 - May 2022	<ul> <li>Student Research Assistant   Eleanor Roosevelt Papers Project</li> <li>Transcribe, proofread, research, &amp; edit scholarly books &amp; prepare for publication.</li> <li>Manage database of documents and organize for future database redesign.</li> </ul>
Sep 2021 - May 2022	<ul> <li>Climate Intern   Montgomery County Executive Office Climate Team</li> <li>Create designs for monthly newsletter layout, graphics, and website redesign.</li> <li>County climate data analysis &amp; visualization.</li> </ul>
May 2021 - Nov 2021	<ul> <li>UX Engineering Intern   Rocket Mortgage Spark Design System</li> <li>Programming &amp; design work to make company products accessible &amp; user-friendly.</li> <li>Develop webpage; conduct user interviews, design in Adobe XD, and code in React.</li> </ul>
Jan 2020 - May 2021	<ul> <li>Student IT Technician   GW Tech Services &amp; Video Production Center</li> <li>Provide IT support over the phone with remote tools, BeyondTrust and ServiceNow.</li> <li>Help with Audio/Video equipment, editing in Premiere, &amp; other Adobe programs.</li> </ul>
PROJECTS	
Jul 2022 - Jan 2023	Slide Deck Design & Focus Group Data Visualization   Plant-Based Meat Company
Jul 2022 - Aug 2022	Graphic Design & Data Visualization   NATO Report on Media Literacy
Aug 2021 - May 2022	Mobile App Design & Development   Trashi Recycling Education App - Capstone
Apr 2020 - Apr 2021	Head Game Artist & Animator   We The Pixies Online Multiplayer Game

### **EDUCATION**

## B.S. in Computer Science | Minors in Sustainability & Psychology

George Washington University - 2018-2022 - GPA: 3.8

### **AWARDS**

- Graduated Summa Cum Laude 2022
- UX Certification for Persuasive & Emotional Design -NN/g - 2021